# Ana Maria Roberts UX/UI + PRODUCT + BRAND

https://anamariag04.github.io/ana-roberts-site/

Designer with knowledge in HTML, CSS and JavaScript.

10+ years of expertise elevating user experiences and driving business success through a commitment to empathy, emotional design, and design thinking.

Creating and innovating, considering aesthetics and powerful branding strategies.

### CONTACT



+447895339415



anamariag04@gmail.com



/anamariag04



Preston, UK.

### LANGUAGES

English Spanish

### SKILLS & TOOLS

### Personal skills

Leadership skills Empathic Problem solver Proactive Committed

### **UX Skills**

Creative
User research
Emotional design
Personas
Competitive analysis
Prototyping
Usability testing
Brand design

### Tools

Adobe creative cloud, Figma, Adobe XD, Marvel, HTML, JavaScript, CSS and Microsoft

**3D:** Rhinoceros, Solid Works Vray, Blender.

### EDUCATION

## UX Design + Front end development

CareerFoundry GE 2023

### MA In Design by Creative Practice

(Graduate with honours) Liverpool Hope University UK 2015

### BA In Industrial Design El Bosque University

COL 2012

### RECENT UX/UI PROJECT

#### All-in-ONE app

09/2022 - 07/2023

Mobile app that can help users to manage all their main financial tasks and bank accounts in one place.

Design thinking process was the main research method as well as doing surveys, interviews, usability testing to understand, define, and ideate user needs and goals.

Moving on to creation of prototypes and iterating them according to personas needs, journeys, aesthetics, and usability, to provide effective and satisfactory results to users.

### WORK EXPERIENCE

### Senior/Lead product designer

Singleton Trading-Sinco, UK | 12/2018 - Present

- Create, design, and produce over hundreds of thousands of products for the most recognized retailers and children's brands around the world.
- Satisfying customers and working for brands such as, Mattel, Little tikes, LOL, Rainbow High, Paw patrol etc... and retailers such as, Harrods, Walmart, Tesco, Aldi, Carrefour, Hamleys, among others.
- Conduct research, analyze and create successful designs according to the customer and business needs, launching approx. 7 new lines per month.
- Create brands and style guides to bring on trend designs ensuring that identity and brand values are being kept. Conducting A/B testing, surveys, and interviews.
- Contribute to the development and optimisation of processes considering quality, cost, and resources. Speeding up processes by 60% per line without affecting any other factors.

### Senior product designer

8th Wonder Ltd, UK | 12/2014 - 12/2018

- This job consisted in research, design, and creation of children's products for the main retailers mainly in the UK. Such as, Aldi, Asda, Morrisons.
- Contributed to innovate and build up communication with the far east to deliver user friendly products and services considering their techniques and resources.
- Improved branding and created style guides, product/services for Aldi EU and UK.
- Oversaw and approved products to be launched considering licensors, stake holders and business goals.
- Launched 1/3rd of a hero product range every year.